Before delving into the details of scoring functions,
在详细讲解评分函数之前
we need to make a distinction of the two major types of attention.
我们需要区分下两种主要注意力类型
These are often referred to as "Additive Attention and Multiplicative Attention."
通常称之为加法注意力和乘法注意力
Sometimes they're also called "Bahdanau Attention" and "Luong
有时候也称为 Bahdanau 注意力和 Luong 注意力
Attention," referring to the first authors of the papers, which described them.
它们以首次描述这两种类型的论文作者命名
Bahdanau attention refers to Dzmitry Badanau,
Bahdanau 注意力是指 Dzmitry Badanau
the first author of the paper,
他是这篇论文的第一作者
"Neural machine translation by jointly learning to
“Neural machine translation by jointly learning to”
align and translate," which proposed a lot of these ideas.
“align and translate”这篇论文提出了大量这种观点
The scoring function in Bahdanau attention looks like this,
Bahdanau 注意力中的评分函数看起来这样
where h of j is the hidden state from the encoder,
其中 hj 表示编码器的隐藏状态
s of i minus one is the hidden state of the decoder in the previous time step.
s(i-1) 表示上个时间步的解码器隐藏状态
u of a, W of a, and v of a,
Ua Wa 和 va
are all weight matrices that are learned during the training process.
都是在训练流程中学习的权重矩阵
Basically, this is a scoring function,
本质上 这个评分函数
which takes the hidden state of the encoder,
会获取编码器的隐藏状态
hidden state of the decoder,
和解码器的隐藏状态
and produces a single number for each decoder time step.
然后在每个解码器时间步生成一个数字
If this looks too complicated, don't worry about it.
如果看起来太复杂 也不用担心
We'll get into more detail and with a visual explanation as well.
我们将详细讲解该公式并用图形讲解
The scores are then passed into softmax,
然后将得分传入 softmax 中
this is what softmax looks like,
softmax 公式是这样的
and then this is our weighted sum operation,
这是加权求和运算
where we multiply each encoder hidden state,
我们将每个编码器隐藏状态与其得分相乘
by its score, and then we sum them all up,
然后求所有值的和
producing our attention context vector.
生成注意力语境向量
In their architecture, the encoder is a bidirectional RNN,
在它们的结构中 编码器是双向 RNN
and they produce the encoder vector by concatenating the states of these two layers.
通过将这两个图层的状态相连生成编码器向量
Multiplicative attention or Luong attention,
乘法注意力或 Luong 注意力
referring to Thang Luong,
是指 Thang Luong
the first author of the paper,
即以下论文的第一作者
"Effective Approaches to Attention-based Neural Machine Translation."
”Effective Approaches to Attention-based Neural Machine Translation.“
Luong attention built on top of
Luong 注意力以 Bahdanau 注意力为基础
the Bahdanau attention by adding a couple more scoring function.
在其中添加了几个评分函数
Their architecture is also different and that they used
它们的结构也不同 它们仅使用
only the hidden states from the top RNN layer in the encoder.
编码器中顶部 RNN 图层的隐藏状态
This allows the encoder and the decoder to both be stacks of RNNs,
使得编码器和解码器都是 RNN 堆栈
which we'll see later in the applications videos,
稍后我们将在应用视频中看到这一点
which led to some of the premier models that are in production right now.
推动了目前正在生产阶段的一些首发模型的推出
The scoring functions in multiplicative attention are three that we can choose from.
乘法注意力中有三个评分函数可供选择
The simplest one is the dot scoring function,
最简单的是点乘评分函数
which is multiplying the hidden states of the encoder by the hidden state of the decoder.
即将编码器的隐藏状态与解码器的隐藏状态相乘
The second scoring function is called general,
第二个评分函数称为通用评分函数
it builds on top of it and just adds a weight matrix between them,
它以上面的函数为基础 只向其中添加了权重矩阵
and this multiplication in
点积中的这个乘法
the dot product is where multiplicative attention gets its name.
正是乘法注意力的得名原因
The third is very similar to Bahdanau attention,
第三个与 Bahdanau 注意力很相似
in that it adds up the hidden state of the encoder with the hidden state of the decoder,
它将编码器的隐藏状态与解码器的隐藏状态相加
and so this addition is where additive attention gets its name,
这个加法正是加法注意力的得名原因
then multiplies it by a weight matrix,
然后乘以权重矩阵
applies a tanh activation and then multiplies it by another weight matrix.
应用双曲正切激活函数 然后乘以另一个权重矩阵
So, this is a function that we give the hidden state of the decoder at
我们为这个时间步的解码器隐藏状态
this time step and the hidden states of the encoder at all the time steps,
和所有时间步的编码器隐藏状态应用这个函数
and it will produce a score for each one of them.
并为每个状态生成一个得分
We then do softmax just as we did before,
然后像之前一样应用 softmax
and then that would produce c of t here,
生成这里的 ct
they are called the attention context vector,
它们称为注意力语境函数
and so this is the step that would produce the final output of the decoder.
这一步将生成解码器的最终输出
Again, if this doesn't make a lot of sense right now,
如果看不懂这些公式的话
don't worry about it, we'll look at it more visually in the next video.
不用担心 我们将在下个视频中以图形的形式讲解一遍
This is an example from the paper that gives an illustration about
这是论文中的一个示例
attention methods compared to previous sequence to sequence models without attention.
它比较了注意力方法和之前不具有注意力机制的序列到序列模型
So, this is an English to German translation,
这是英语到德语翻译
this is the source English phrase, this is the reference,
这是英文原文 这是参考
this is the label correct German translation,
这是标签正确德语翻译
this is what their model did.
这是模型的流程
So, it translated it very well,
翻译得很好
and this is the the base or the benchmark model without attention,
这是没有注意力机制的基准模型
where we see it got the name Luong.
可以看出姓名翻错了
This is something we can attribute to the difficulty of capturing
这个错误可以归结于
all the information just in the last hidden state of the encoder.
难以获取最后一个编码器隐藏状态中的所有信息
This is one of the powerful things that attention does.
这是注意力机制的强大之处
It gives the encoder the ability to look at parts of the input sequence,
使编码器能够查看输入序列的各个部分
no matter how far back they were in the input sequence.
无论它们在输入序列的前面哪个位置